The headline section and the summary sections
标题和个人简述
are the most important part of your profile.
是你简历最重要的部分
This is where potential connections, corporate recruiters,
它们是潜在人脉、企业雇主、
and anyone viewing your profile will get to know more about your previous experience,
或任何浏览你简历的人进一步了解你的过往经历、
skills, interests, and other vital information about you.
技能、兴趣和其它关键信息的途径
The headline is the very first thing seen by another viewer.
标题是其它浏览者看到的第一条信息
Your headline should be an attention grabber of how you would
你的标题要能引人注意 仿佛可以
get someone to stop and listen to what you have to say.
使人驻足倾听你想说的话
Using keywords in your headline such as
在标题中使用关键词 比如全栈网页开发工程师
full-stack web developer would be a great headline as it clearly states who you are,
就是个很好的标题 它清晰陈述了你是谁
and has multiple keywords for others to find you.
还包含其它关键词让别人能找到你
In this example, full-stack, web developer,
这个例子中 全栈、网页开发
and full-stack web developer are three separate phrases that
和全栈网页开发工程师是分开的关键词
can trigger recruiters word search and bringing it to their attention.
会在雇主搜索相关词汇时出现 让他们注意到你
If you wanted a slightly more personable headline,
如果你想要一个稍带个人色彩的标题
you could put something like dedicated full-stack developer,
你可以用类似“全心投入的全栈工程师
bringing education into the 21st century.
引领教育进入21世纪”的标题
This headline doesn't have the number of keywords as the first headline,
这个标题不像第一个有那么多关键词
but it definitely puts a personalized spin to your introduction.
但它一定能让你的简介更有个人特点
The best option for a headline is the job title you're currently applying to,
标题的最佳选择就是你正在应聘的职业头衔
as this should give you the best chances of being recognized within that network.
因为这使你最大可能地被那个圈子注意
Now that you've gotten someone's attention,
现在已经有人注意到你
use your summary to tell them who you are,
那就用个人简述告诉他们你是谁
what you've done, and what you're looking for.
你做过什么 正在寻求什么
This is the best place to use your elevator speech.
这里就需要用到电梯演讲的能力
If you created an effective speech,
如果你的演讲有效
it should pretty much addressed the who you are,
那它很大程度讲的就是你是谁
the what you've done,
你曾做过哪些事
and what you're looking for.
你在寻求什么
Part of what you've done is your work here with Udacity.
在优达的经历是你做过的事之一
Use your classroom projects as part of your summary.
把课程项目当成个人简述的一部分
Your project shows that you have hands-on experience.
你的项目显示出你在这一领域的实践经验
Just like with any other form of education,
就像其它形式的教育
use your time at Udacity as a marketing tool to branch out into new networks.
把你在优达花的时间作为推广工具进入新的社交圈
Add your Nano degree program with the rest of your education experience.
把纳米学位加入你的教育经历里
Not only will using Udacity help you grow your network,
优达的经历不仅能帮你扩大人脉圈
we also have hiring partners who are actively
我们还有招聘伙伴积极寻找
searching for graduates to fill needed openings.
优达毕业生填补职位空缺
Even if they aren't our hiring partners,
即使雇主不是我们的招聘伙伴
employers recognize the talent and hard work that is required to successfully complete
他们也会认可成功获得纳米学位所需的
Nano degree programs here and are looking for
天赋和勤奋 并期待你把这份
you to bring that talent and hard work to their organization.
天赋和勤奋带到他们公司的工作
When writing your summary,
撰写个人简述时 如果可能
keep your experience and education down to three to five bullet statements if possible.
把教育和工作经历提炼成三至五条用着重符号标示的句子
If you have a long experience or education background,
如果你的工作和教育背景很长
use the examples to strategically position yourself for the role you want.
那就有策略地使用例子来展示你适合应聘的职位
Don't just tell your story, sell your potential.
不要只是讲故事 强调自己有潜力
Wherever possible, use hard numbers and
只要有可能 用实在的数字
quantifiable facts instead of using vague and general statements.
和具体事实而不是大而空泛的陈述
Always use active language instead of passive.
永远使用积极表达而非消极表达
For example, the bullet statement,
比如 着重符号后面句子陈述
"Had created content for Career Services at you
"曾在优达事业服务部创造内容
Udacity to help students prepare for their job hunt,
帮助学生准备求职过程中的人脉扩展、
networking, resume, and interviews in order to help
简历、面试 帮他们获得
them find new jobs," can be rewarded for concreteness,
新的工作。” 这个陈述如果能更具体
conciseness, and active language.
精简、使用积极语言会更好
A better statement would sound something like,
更有效的陈述应该像这样
"Engaged 10,000 plus new students in
“组织超过10,000名学生参加
job search courses by improving content offerings on networking,
求职课程 并提供扩展人脉
job application, and interview best practices."
申请工作 面试礼仪方面的内容"
Not only does the second statement cut out filler words like,
第二种陈述删除了毫无内容的虚词
to help or in order to,
如“帮助”、“为了”
it also contains quantifiable numbers and action verbs like engaged and improving.
还包含了实在的数字以及“组织”、“提高”等动词
Using these techniques will improve the strength of your summary and display
这些技巧会让你的个人简述更有力并展示
the experience and confidence gained from your past roles.
你从过往工作中收获的经验和能力
Many of the points I would make about writing a resume would
我在撰写简历课程中讲过的很多注意点
equally apply to grading the LinkedIn summary.
也适用于写领英的个人简述
The main difference between writing a resume and writing the summary
写简历和写简述最主要的区别是
is that the summary is a narrative and considerably shorter.
简述是一段叙述 并且要简短很多
Choose your words carefully and concisely.
选词要审慎精简
Last but not least,
最后一点也很重要
place a call to action with your contact information at the end of your summary.
在简述最后的联系方式上设计一个行动号召式的话术
Encourage the reader to reach out to you in whatever form you prefer,
鼓励阅读者用你希望的方式联系你
email, text, phone calls, et cetera.
可以是邮件、短信、电话等
Don't let them leave your profile without compelling them
不要忘记提醒他们离开简历页面前
to want to contact you to discuss things in more detail.
要联系你进一步讨论